

· SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER · SECURITY ENGINEER · MACHINE LEARNING EXPERT · SOLUTIONS AND CLOUD ARCHITECT ·

Kochi, Kerala, INDIA, 683520 | Dubai, United Arab Emirates

□ (+971) 3934604 | 🗷 afvamj@gmail.com | 🖸 Afvan Moopen | 🛅 Afvan Moopen | 💆 @afvan.m

"Placed in between organizations and technology, I am committed and enthusiastic in what I do. Driven by great challenges and learning opportunities, I look forward to combining technical knowledge with interpersonal skills."

Summary_

I am self learner and working confident, curious, and perpetually. I have good experience in developing software platforms for real world problems, and I am working on several communities for improving the Technical knowledge in the society. I have good leadership, organizing, And communication skills. I am a perfectionist. I want to solve the Problems in my hands in perfect ways, which is, however, not achievable in many situations. I also apply Bellman Equation in the optimization of my life, which is a Markov decision process, but the future discount factor γ in the Equation might be small and I would often be trapped in local optimum

Education

VIT University Vellore

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE ENGINEERING, SPECIALISATION IN GAMING TECHNOLOGY

Apr. 2018 - Nov. 2022

BTECH with Specialization on Gaming and Advanced Cyber Technology

University of Oxford Remote

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT, DEVOPS, DATA ANALYSIS

Jan. 2020 - Dec. 2020

• Oxford eLearning Batch Community (Diploma), Advanced Cyber Security, Artificial Intelligence

Massachusetts Institute of Technology

Domoto

MACHINE LEARNING AND MICRO-SERVICES DEVELOPMENT, END-TO-END CLOUD COMPUTING, SOCIAL DATA SCIENTIST

Feb. 2021 - Mar. 2021

• Data Structures and ALgorithms. Machine Learning and Big Data End-to-End Networking and Security Cloud Technology(AWS, GCP, Azure

Work Experience

ELV Alliance US. Remote

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEERING LEAD

Jan. 2021 - PRESENT

- Knowledge of Computer Science fundamentals such as object-oriented design, algorithm design, data structures, problem solving, and complexity analysis
- Experience in web/mobile application development, Unix/Linux environments, distributed/parallel systems, information retrieval, networking, or systems/security software development
- C, NET, C, C++, Java, Javascript/Typescript, Python, Data Analysis packages, Machine Learning Packages, Cloud Solution AWS, GCP, AZURE, Xamarin Dev

Alliance UAE

CHIEF FULL STACK ENGINEER May 2020 - 2020 July

- Working knowledge in a technology domain such as distributed internet-scale web or mobile applications, DevOps, Serverless, Big Data, Analytics, Machine Learning, enterprise workloads (SAP, VMware, Windows etc.), high-performance databases (SQL and/or NoSQL), networking implementations, highly secured workloads
- Experience with distributed, multi-tiered systems, algorithms, and relational databases

International Airlines Group

UAL

 ${\sf Software\ Developer\ and\ Security\ Tester(Pen-Test)}$

July 2021 - PRESENT

- Effectively articulate technical challenges and solutions, Extensive knowledge of security technology, risk assessment methodologies
- Experience in optimization mathematics such as linear programming and nonlinear optimization. Brilliant at policies, systems, Network
- Adept at handling ambiguous or undefined problems as well as ability to think abstractly

Skills_

Java, C/C++, C, Objective C, Python, JavaScript/Typescript, Go , Ruby , Scala , Web/mobile application development, Unix/Linux

Worked on environments, distributed/parallel systems, information retrieval, networking, Systems and Security software development, Rust

, Data Structures and Algorithms , Familiar with majority of the Web Development frameworks, Security Frameworks

Languages English, Hindi, Kannada, Malayalam, Arabic, Tamil

Certifications and Trainings(Major)

2020	Certified Blockchain expert, Blockchain Council	Remote
2020	IABAC Certifications, Data Analysis, Artificial Intelligence Expert	Remote
2020	Blue and Red Teaming Certification,	Remote
2021	Nvidia Certification (Specialist,Ambassador) ,	Remote
2021	VMware Certifications and Training(VmWare Expert),	Remote
2020	AWS Certifications and Training(Solution Architect),	Remote
2020	Qualys Certifications and Training(Cloud Agent , Policy Compliance , End Point Detection Response(EDR)),	Remote
	Google Certifications (Network Professional , Tensorflow Expert , Tensorflow End-to-End Cloud	
2020	Applications, Mobile Web Specialist, Aanalytics, Digital Marketing, Cloud Data Engineering,	Remote
	Network Engineer),	
2021	Apple Certifications and Trainings (Security Architecture, Design Architecture),	Remote
2020	Certified Associate in SCRUM fundamentals(CASF),	Remote
2020	Huawei Certification (OpenCloud , Data Mining , Network and Security , IOT, 5G Expert),	Remote
2020	Micrososft Certifications(AZ-900 , AI-900 , DP-900 , Advertising Certified professional , .NET Developer , Xamarin Developer , Azure Cloud Security),	Remote
2020	Cisco Certification (CCNA, CCDE , Automation)),	Remote
2020	Oracle Certifications(Database Maintainer , Leadership role , Cloud),	Remote
2020	Intel Certifications(ARM Developer ,Winx64 Programming),	Remote
2020	Offensive Security Training(OSCP, OSWE, OSCD),	Remote
2020	Red Hat Training(Red Hat Operation),	Remote
2020	Cloudera Certifications (Big Data Analysis),	Remote

Projects, Publications & Courses

Cublocks: Ethereum based secured crypto wallet video Sharing Application

Congress of Computer Engineering

"SECURED CRYPTO VIDEO SHARING APPLICATION"

Nov. 2021

Aug. 2021

· Personal Project

AWS-VERIZON HACKATHON

- Winner of the award: CryptoMath Category
- · Winner of the award: "Best Blockchain-chosen project"

Fake-Face AI Animator (GANS)

Github : Afvan Moopen

MIT - PROJECT

• Al -Animator which helps people bring back to life with just their portray

One Life Hackathon

EMERGENCY ASSISTANT - SOS (XAMARIN - XCODE - ANDROID - ELECTRON)

May. 2021

• Emergency App with Cloud support for maximum fast emergency Delivery using Map facility - SOS App

Enter UAE

• Quick inApp Entertainment and Monitoring (I)on Vehicle-Vehicle Communication in 5G using AWS Wavelength

Advanced Network Analyzer.

PLATFORM TO ANALYZE AND MONITOR NETWORK DEVICES (ADVANCED PYTHON, GO, REACT, FLASK, SQLALCHEMY,

Jul. 2021

Labs

Aug. 2021

Mongodb, ncclient, pyshark, Threading, Java Host Monitor).

• A fully functional App using Cloud Service and WebSocket architecture providing Realtime communications and later provide suggestion to the prescription using Intelligent Services from AWS

JaraHelping Community Wipe Fraud

JAVA NUERAL NETWORK LIBRARY

Aug. 2020

• A Fully Build Java NN library)

Sight-3DHelping Community wipe Frauds

Python 3D Math Library Aug. 2020

• An Elegant Style Math - 3D library with help ... Three.js in Python